# Karina Rojas

## Data scientist | Researcher

Data scientist with 10 years experience in research: data processing, visualisation, analysis and model building as well data catalog manipulation and analysis and utilization of simple SQL queries.

Member of international collaboration as EUCLID consortium and LSST-UK Junior Associate as well DSFP-LSST Data Science Fellowship Alumni. Commited, enthusiastic learner and open-minded.

Dornacherstrasse 27, 4500, Solothurn, Switzerland



karina.rojasolate@gmail.com



+41 79 373 2903



<u>karina-rojas-olate</u>



Krojas



Residence permit B, with right to work in Switzerland

### **Work Experience**

#### University of Portsmouth | Fellow researcher

Oct 2021 - To date | Institute of Cosmology and Gravitation, Portsmouth, UK.

- Design, execution and statistical analysis of an innovative experiment to evaluate the performance of human in image classification and compared their results with neural network classification.
- Train a neural network (autoencoder) for efficiently extract specific features in a large dataset of images.
- Development of a pipeline for processing and combining images.

### Ecole Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne | Posdoctoral researcher Oct 2018 -Sep 2021 | Laussane, Switzerland.

- Classification of images using convolutional neural networks.
- Participation in the development team of several codes including the automatization of a modeling pipeline and the development of a visualization tool.
- Mentoring graduate students in their project and/or master thesis.
- Weekly colloquium organizer.

#### Universidad de Valparaíso | Doctoral researcher

2014-2018 | Valparaíso, Chile.

- Develope of several codes including a pipeline for complex time series analysis to indirect measure astronomical features, a code for spectral analysis of astronomical data and the application of machine learning techniques for clustering.
- Several nights observing at different telescope. The task performed include: night planning, telescope preparation, observing targets and calibration images, and solving fast technical problems.

#### Star Tres | Co-founder

2013-To date | Online.

- Astronomical social media content creation for general public, with the purpose of education and women in science visualization.
- Execution of public talks and workshops in low incomes schools in Chile.

#### **Relevant Skills**

#### **Programming**

Python: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Scipy, Sklearn, Tensorflow, Pytorch, Astropy.

Wolfram Mathematica.

#### Libraries/Platforms

Jupyter Notebooks, Latex, Github, Slack.

#### Communication

Project management, supervision, public speaking, talks in international conferences, outreach events and content creator.

#### Languages

Spanish (Native). English (C1). German (A1). French (A1).

#### **Education**

#### Ph.D. in Astrophysics

2014-2018 | Universidad de Valparaíso.

#### MSC in Astrophysics

2012-2014 | Universidad de Valparaíso.

#### **Bachelor in Physics**

2007-2011 | Universidad de Valparaíso.

#### **Achievements**

#### **Awards**

2018 | "100 Young Chilean Leaders".

2015 | "Graduate Student Prize Lecture".

#### Grants

2020 | IAU-OAD outreach project.

2017 | LSSTC Data Science Fellowship.

2017 | CONICYT Ph.D. grant.